#### Contact

+971554379700 (Mobile) engr.mudassarnazir@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/mudassarnazir (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Healthcare
Early-stage Startups
Start-up Consulting

### Languages

Urdu (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)
Punjabi (Native or Bilingual)

# Mudassar Nazir

CTO at Appstown

Abu Dhabi Emirate, United Arab Emirates

## Summary

• To build great Software Products spend more time on planning over coding:) • •

Mudassar is a highly efficient and reliable professional who possesses a broad skill set in building B2C & B2B technology products and managing early-stage tech startups.

He has great expertise in the software development process ranging from requirement gathering, wireframing, prototyping, and design to development & deployment.

Recently most of his work consists of leading technical teams, by creating an easy development environment, fixing technical debts, providing best practices code examples, and mentoring devs.

letsconsult.me/mudassar-nazir-cto

## Experience

Appstown

CTO & Managing Director September 2021 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

We build business-driven websites & mobile apps using the latest and scaleable technologies.

Rental Shield Chief Technology Officer June 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Protect & manage your Rental Deposits. You can change so much with just machine-analyzed photos....

Founder Institute UAE & GCC
MVP Development / Engineering Mentor
June 2021 - June 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

The Founder Institute is the world's largest pre-seed startup accelerator. Since 2009, we have helped over 5,000 entrepreneurs get the focus and support needed to build a business that matters. Based in Silicon Valley and with chapters across 90 countries, the Founder Institute's mission is to empower communities of talented and motivated people to build impactful technology companies worldwide.

Doctors Group Ltd.

1 year 7 months

Project Team Lead

August 2020 - June 2021 (11 months)

Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Full Stack Engineer
December 2019 - July 2020 (8 months)
Abu Dhabi. United Arab Emirates

- -Build & Launched the various health tech products, built from scratch using React JS, Node JS, Lit-element, Graphql, Php, Mysql.
- -Creating Wireframes and Prototypes of every new feature before development using Adobe Experience Design (XD).
- -Implemented a tech startup structure in the company Hiring developers for the team.
- -Conducts regular market research to keep the products technically updated.
- -Helping technical teams to keep the product Search engine & User experience friendly.
- -Integrated and maintaining the telemedicine solutions using Amazon chime.
- -Developed a Medical Chatbot named "Dakhtar" which acts as a virtual doctor and can speak different dialects of Arabic (Emirati and Classic Arabic).

-Managing to develop the new features and custom requests from the market related to each specific product.

-Helping the operations team in task automation , to speed up some operations using python.

Skull Saver
Co-Founder & IOT Engineer
September 2017 - December 2020 (3 years 4 months)
Punjab, Pakistan

Skull saver is a vision to save the lives of careless people and reduce the billion dollars healthcare cost.

According to the NHTSA Moreover, if all motorcyclists had worn helmets in 2017, an additional \$1.5 billion in economic costs and \$8.9 billion in comprehensive costs could have been saved.

According to WHO, More than 90% of road traffic deaths occur in low- and middle-income countries and the most affordable way of transportation in these countries is motorbikes.

We developed a working prototype of an intelligent helmet, which will make sure everyone will wear the helmet while riding a bike.

If someone does not wear a helmet, he can not start the motorbike.

Fortunately, bike helmets reduce the risk of head injury by at least 45%, brain injury by 33%, facial injury by 27%, and fatal injury by 29%.

Tech4Biz Solutions Private Limited
Full-stack Developer
January 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 11 months)
United States

- -Designed & Developed various web applications using Html, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Php, Codeigniter.
- -Transform business requirements into reusable UI components following UI designer guidelines.

- -PSD to Html, Responsive & Pixel Perfect frontend designing of mobile & web apps.
- -Developed hybrid mobile apps using lonic.
- -Designed business static & dynamic websites using WordPress and custom Html, CSS.
- -Written some scripts for task automation using python.
- -Led effort to develop companion application programming interface (API) for a web app, to facilitate third-party plugins.

Freelancer.com
Full Stack Developer
February 2017 - December 2017 (11 months)
United States

Freelancer.com is the world's largest freelancing and crowdsourcing marketplace by a number of users and projects. It connects over 50,603,025 employers and freelancers globally from over 247 countries, regions, and territories. Through its marketplace, employers can hire freelancers to do work in areas such as software development, writing, data entry, and design right through to engineering, the sciences, sales and marketing, accounting, and legal services.

MY Responsibilities »»

- ✓ Designing & Development of B2C and B2B applications.
- √ Worked on User Interfaces and Experience, Technical SEO & code
  optimization.
- ✓ Designed Responsive & Pixel Perfect fronted of mobile & web apps.
- ✓ Requirements Gathering & Analysis, Deployment.
- ✓ Database (Mysql) , Server Management , Developed Web Services ( Rest & Soap API,s ).
- ✓ Developed Mobile Apps using Ionic .
- ✓ Worked on web security, Google, Here Maps, Twillio, & other third party Services.

Fiverr Frontend Developer February 2017 - December 2017 (11 months)

Pakistan

Fiverr is an online platform that allows buyers and sellers to connect so they can buy and sell digital services. I was providing website development services to the clients

## Education

University of Gujrat

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Software Engineering · (2013 - 2017)